A Guide to the John A. Pino papers FA1301
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Foundation and Rutgers Poultry Projects, 1950-1983; 4
  - Meeting in Germany with Sterling Wortman, 1970-1971; 2012:067:041 (Box 16, Folder 171, Item 2012:067:041)
  - Report on Potential for Agricultural Sciences Program Activities in Sub-Saharan Africa, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Unidentified Photographs from Binder, Nigeria?, undated; 2012:067:042 (Box 16, Folder 172, Item 2012:067:042)
  - Agricultural Sciences Staff Seminar, Williamsburg, undated; 2012:067:043 (Box 16, Folder 173, Item 2012:067:043)
    Joe Ropert, John Pino, and Edwin Welhausen
  - Unidentified photographs, Nigeria?, undated; 2012:067:044 (Box 16, Folder 174, Item 2012:067:044)
    Note from envelope that held pictures: Joe Black second from left
  - Photo Album Labelled Mexico Workshop, undated; 2012:067:045 (Box 17, Folder 175, Item 2012:067:045)
  - International Laboratory for Research on Animal Diseases (ILRAD): A Pictorial History Compiled by the Rockefeller Foundation Volume I-IV, 1978 April; 2012:067:046 (Box 17, Folder 176-179, Item 2012:067:046, Box 18, Folder 180)
  - Research at La Campana - Chivaus, Mexico photographs, undated; 2012:067:047 (Box 18, Folder 181, Item 2012:067:047)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting in Mexico - Reviewing Activities of International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT) photographs, undated; 2012:067:048 (Box 18, Folder 182-183, Item 2012:067:048)
  - John Pino, Professor at Rutgers University, Portrait, undated; 2012:067:049 (Box 18, Folder 184, Item 2012:067:049)
  - Photographs of Pino with Former Students, undated; 2012:067:050 (Box 18, Folder 185, Item 2012:067:050)
    Note on back of photo: Robert Enz (student), Ralph Brinston (student), John Pino, Rod Reincke (student), ?
  - Photograph of John Pino with Ralph Brinster, undated; 2012:067:051 (Box 18, Folder 186, Item 2012:067:051)
    University of Pennsylvania Veterinary School commencement, Brinster was a former student of Pino
  - Thailand - Farm Suwan photographs, undated; 2012:067:053 (Box 18, Folder 188, Item 2012:067:053)
  - Thailand - Inauguration of Suwan Research Farm photographs, undated; 2012:067:054 (Box 18, Folder 189, Item 2012:067:054)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Work with Veterinary School in Peru, 1979 August; 2012:067:055 (Box 18, Folder 190, Item 2012:067:055)
  - Review of Program in Amadu Bello University Nigeria photographs, undated; 2012:067:056 (Box 18, Folder 191, Item 2012:067:056)
    Caption on back of one photo: left John Pino, 2nd left Glenn Beck, Far Right Martin Gonzalez
  - John Pino Portraits, undated; 2012:067:058 (Box 18, Folder 193, Item 2012:067:058)
  - Norman Borlaug Signed Portrait, 1968 January 22; 2012:067:059 (Box 18, Folder 194, Item 2012:067:059)
    Note on photo: To John, Thanks for everything, Norm Borlaug 1/22/68
  - Gadjah Mada University, Indonesia, photographs, undated; 2012:067:060 (Box 18, Folder 195, Item 2012:067:060)
    Note for one photo: Jim Thompson - left, Rockefeller Foundation Representative to Gadjah Mada
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Bellagio Meetups Group Photographs, 1969-1982; 2012:067:061 (Box 19, Folder 196, Item 2012:067:061)
    Notes on photos: "Parasites in the Gut" - October 1-5, 1978, Bellagio Strengthening Food Policy - November 5, 1982, Villa Conference on East Coast Fever - October 13-16, 1969
  - John Pino and George Harrar Photographs, undated; 2012:067:062 (Box 19, Folder 197, Item 2012:067:062)
    Note on one photo: John: We have shared many experiences since you joined us in Mexico. Currently your leadership at the Conquest of Hunger program of the RF and your association with the IADS have helped importantly in the worldwide effort to improve food production. With admiration and affection - George
  - Ecuador Photographs, undated; 2012:067:063 (Box 19, Folder 198, Item 2012:067:063)
    Photographs of Ulysses Gerry Grant, Enrique Ampuero, John Pino, and Fabian Portilla
  - Rockefeller Foundation Brazil - University of Bahia, undated; 2012:067:064 (Box 19, Folder 199, Item 2012:067:064)
    Photos of RF program director and Mascarenhas
  - International Research Laboratory - Kenya - Consultative Group for International Agricultural Research (CGIAR), 1976 July 21; 2012:067:065 (Box 19, Folder 200, Item 2012:067:065)
    Note attached to one photo: With the compliments of Professor Ian McIntyre (on left), Dean of the Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, University Veterinary School, Beardsden Road, Beardsden, Glasgow G61 1QH
  - Rockefeller Foundation Sheep Project in West Virginia with University of West Virginia, undated; 2012:067:066 (Box 19, Folder 201, Item 2012:067:066)
  - US Agricultural Task Force Commission in Peru - Yeutter, photographs, 1982; 2012:067:067 (Box 19, Folder 202, Item 2012:067:067)
    Part of the Presidential Agricultural Mission under President Ronald Reagan led by Clayton Yeutter
  - International Laboratory for Research and Animal Diseases (ILRAD) - Cattle in Nigeria photographs, undated; 2012:067:068 (Box 19, Folder 203, Item 2012:067:068)
    One photograph is captioned "Cattle in Colombia"
  - Visit in Sonora, Mexico - Board Meeting photographs, 1983; 2012:067:069 (Box 19, Folder 204, Item 2012:067:069)
  - Construction of Centro Internacional de Agricultura Tropical (CIAT) International Center for Tropical Agriculture photographs, undated; 2012:067:070 (Box 19, Folder 205, Item 2012:067:070)
  - Photograph of John Knowles, Sterling Wortman, and John Pino, undated; 2012:067:071 (Box 19, Folder 206, Item 2012:067:071)
  - Mexico, International Potato Center (CIP) photographs, undated; 2012:067:072 (Box 19, Folder 207, Item 2012:067:072)
    Includes photos of Telles Giron, Daniel Hagan, John Pino, the Instituto de Investigacion, Henk Teunessin, Ned Raun, and Animal Science Staff in Mexico
  - Gene Bank in China Slides and Photographs, undated; 2012:067:073 (Box 19, Folder 208, Item 2012:067:073)
    Captions: Transporting a sick woman by using traditional equipment; Consultation and health education in the polyclinic
  - Framed Photograph of John Pino and Sterling Wortman, undated; 2012:067:074 (Box 19, Folder 209, Item 2012:067:074)
  - Scrapbook - "Fotos", 1964; 2017:067:075; Oversized Photo Album/Scrapbook (Box 20, Item 2017:067:075)
    Clippings and photographs, Note describing scrapbook: page 1: unknown, Agosto Aguilera, Martin Gonzalez, Pedro Solana, John Ping; page 2: Pedro Solana, Eduardo Rivera, Emil Arias, unknown, Agosto Aguilera, FAO seated at table head, Dan Hagen, Oscar Valdez Ornelas, John Pino, Edsel Bixter, Henk Tunissien; page 3: upper left John Pino, Martin Gonzalez, Gilbert Valdez, Ned Raun, Henk Tunissien, Oscar Valdez Ornelas, center Ned Raun, Gilberto Valdez, lower left Ned Raun Gilberto Valdez, and Martin Gonzalez; page 3: upper right Dan Hagen lower right Ned Raun Gilberto Valdez, John Pino, Oscar Ornelas, Dan Hagen, Hank Tuniessin, Group photo with Livestock Association - Chihuahua, Group photo - meeting at Veterinary School - Mexico 3rd left Oscar Ornelas, Ernesto Bachtold, Pablo Zikrold, John Pino; Meeting with Subsecretary of livestock Mexico City center Oscar Ornelas right Acevedos, National Inst. Livestock Research - Palo Alto, Mexico center President Adolfo Lopez Mateas right of president - Inginero Julian Rodriguez Adams, John Pino; President of Mexico and Livestock Association; top left l-r - Agosto Aguilera, Alexander Cuadra, John Pino, bottom John Pino giving talk; Picture of John Pino and Ned Raun and newspaper clippings, pictures from experiment station at Chihuahua; group from veterinary school, Ralph Richardson and Doug Barnes (RF staff), John Pino in hat - Chihuahua; Veterinary School staff in Peru, Top left: Dr. Guierlmo Schnazi (veterinarian), Don Davis, and John Pino; ITESM - Dr. Michel, John Pino, director of agronomy school in Monterey; Top left Agronomy School in Monterey, John Pino, director of agronomy school; bottom left: John Pino, Ken Turk; Upper right Ken Turn and staff member from Agronomy School
  - Certificate of Appreciation, Serving as Chairman of the Board of Directors of the International Laboratory for Research on Animal Diseases (ILRAD), 1980 (Box 13, Folder 133)
    Expression of Appreciation for serving ILRAD from November 1973 to March 1980
- National Research Council, Board on Agriculture, and Inter-American Development Bank (IDB), 1984-2001; 5
  - A Discussion Paper: Cooperative Programs Between the International Agricultural Research Centers (IARCs) and the National Agriculatural Research Institutions (NARs) in Research and Training: Decentralizing Research and Training Activities within the Consultative Group for International Agricultural Research (CGIAR) System, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Expert Consultation on the Role of Universities in National Agricultural Research Systems, Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) of the United Nations, Rome, Italy, 1991 March 19-22 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    Keynote Address: The Relationship of National Agricultural Research Systems to International Agricultural Research Centers with Special Reference to Universities by John A. Pino
  - Inter-American Development Bank (IDB) Report - Agricultural Research in Latin America and the Caribbean, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Genetic Resources, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    Contains fact sheets prepared by the International Board for Plant Genetic Resources (IBPGR) on behalf of the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR), Inter-American Institute for Cooperation on Agriculture (IICA) correspondence, and Sistema Nacional de Recursos Geneticos Vegetales - Peru (SINARGEV) 1991
    Contains a floppy disk - Sistemas-Peru
    Access copy currently unavailable. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
  - Global Status of Plant Genetic Resources Report to the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Commission on Plant Genetic Resources, Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO), Fourth and Fifth Sessions, Rome, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - National Research Council - Animal Genetic Resources, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 94)
    Correspondence with Neal A. Jorgensen, Options for Change: An Independent Appraisal of CGIAR Activities in Plant Genetic Resources By David Wood, National Animal Genome Initiative, and Implementation Plans for Joint Animal Germplasm Program/Animal Genome Research Program National Genetics Resources Program Authorized by the 1990 Farm Bill
  - Food, Nutrition, and Agricultural Development, undated (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - National Research Council - National Plant International Potato Council (ICP) Systems, 1989 November (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Rutgers Nutritional Sciences - Beaudette-Thompson Lecture, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Uruguay Paper - La Investigacion Agropecuaria como Apoyo a la Formulacion de Politicas de Desarrollo, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Appropriate Technology International (ATI) - Mexico Enterprises Mid-Term Evaluation Report, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Correspondence - Meshack J. Mbogollo, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Tanzania, Project Photographs, 1998 August 12; 2012:067:028; 25 photographs (Box 15, Folder 158, Item 2012:067:028)
  - Project Proposal - Strengthening Regional Collaboration in Animal Disease and Zoonoses Control in the Middle East, 1996 January-February (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Developments Concerning the International Undertaking on Plant Genetic Resources, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    Contains National Center for Genetic Resources Conference Call - July 2001, Report on Attendance at the Sixth Extraordinary Session of the Commission on Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture, Proposed Section for the Next Farm Bill, Statement to the FAO Conference regarding the adoption of the International Treaty on Plant Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture, and International Treaty on Plant Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture
  - Winrock International Trinational Animal Health Research Project (TAHRP), 1990-1995 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Rutgers Doctor of Science Honorary Degree, 1996 May 16 (Box 12, Folder 121)
  - Agricultural Research in Latin America Draft, 1984 May 15 (Box 12, Folder 122)
  - Reporte de la Evaluacion Final del Proyecto: Desarollo de Microempresesas de Servicios a la Produccion Agropecuaria en la Region de Puebla de Mexico, ATI-Colegio Grant 85-0019, 1990 August (Box 12, Folder 123)
  - Rutgers Oral History Archives of World War II Correspondence, 2000 September 27 (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - Crop Germplasm Resources Management in China, American Society of Agronomy Meeting, 1989 October (Box 13, Folder 127)
  - Report of Mid-Term Evaluation of Project: Development of Microenterprises Providing Services to Agricultural Production in the Puebla Region of Mexico, 1988 September (Box 13, Folder 128)
  - A Discussion Paper: Cooperative Programs Between the International Agricultural Research Centers (IARCs) and the National Agriculatural Research Institutions (NARs) in Research and Training: Decentralizing Research and Training Activities within the Consultative Group for International Agricultural Research (CGIAR) System, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 129)
  - Distinguished Service in the Cause of International Agricultural Development Certificate, Centro Internacional de Agricultura Tropical (CIAT) International Center for Tropical Agriculture, 1985 May 30 (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - United States Department of Agriculture Certificate of Merit, 1984 June 1 (Box 13, Folder 132)